ADRIAN IONITA

0797 187 0684 ↓
adrian@ionita.me
Adrian Ionita
https://github.com/iceiony

profile

Data scientist focused on computational modeling with a strong background in software engineering. Education and industry experience lead to a deep understanding of the scientific and development challenges faced when building artificial intelligence systems. I am able to support companies in data science tasks, develop research concepts and turn them into functional software

tech skills Programming

R, Python, SQL, MATLAB, C/C++, JavaScript, Java, C#, CUDA, Ruby (automation and scripting)

Data Science

Principal Component Analysis, Independent Component Analysis, Fourier Domains, Monte Carlo Simulations, Clustering, Agent Based Modeling, Bayesian Methods, Particle Filters

Machine Learning

Deep Learning (Classification & Regression), RBF Networks, SOM, RNN, Committee Machines, Belief Propagation, Reinforcement Learning, Hebbian Learning, Improving Generalisation & Training Speed

projects Semantic Representation In Human Language, Iceiony Ltd

Sep 2016 - Current

- · Evaluating neural network frameworks, to enable choosing the most appropriate for language processing
- · Debunking the latching problem in recurrent network training, leading to better training methods
- Developing custom sentence tokenising enabling reuse across non-english languages
- Designing unsupervised training techniques for language structure and semantic representation Key Technologies: R, Python, Deep Learning (RNN), PyTorch, Dynet

Telemetry Events Aggregation

Oct 2017 - Current

Implementing efficient processing of telemetry reading on low spec hardware, enabling reporting to business
 Key Technologies: R

Fuel Savings Prediction Model

Jan 2017 - May 2017

- Designing statistical model estimating fuel and repair savings from optimal tire inflation for fleets of vehicles
- Guiding junior analyst in model implementation, teaching good code practices
 Key Technologies: R, Monte Carlo Simulation

Customer Flow Forecasting, Udacity competition

Feb 2017 - Mar 2017

- Organising and leading team members for competition whilst distributed across world
- Flattening large dataset of customer transactions into time series, enabling easier analysis and prediction
- · Analysing frequency domain of sales, gaining insight into customer buying habits
- · Hierarchical and cluster analysis showing similarities in sales between different retailers
- Experimenting with various time series prediction approaches (e.g. ARIMA, ICA & Regression, Neural Networks) leading to solution that placed team in top 10%

Key Technologies: R, ICA, Fourier Domains, Clustering, Regression

Computational Model For Tool Use Reasoning, University of Birmingham

Apr 2016 - Dec 2016

- · Laid foundation for a computational model of human tool use, ensuring future extensibility and development
- Evaluated physics engines for faithful reproduction of real physical interaction, enabling accurate experimentation
- Proposed novel technique for shape matching, that employs surface level correlation to replicate geometric reasoning Key Technologies: C++, MATLAB, Physics Simulation, PCA

Products on Virtual Shelves, Walmart Labs competition

Oct 2016

• Training RBF network on features built from product description to assign products to shelves Key Technologies: MATLAB, PCA, NLP, RBF Networks

Robotic Model For Optimal Gaze Control, University of Birmingham

Dec 2015 - Apr 2016

- Implemented neural network model that learns optimal gaze strategies from environment feedback
- · Model considers sensory uncertainty in its internal belief state when evaluating choices for gaze locations
- Performance is far beyond random gaze, improving time efficiency by reducing number of ocular fixations Key Technologies: MATLAB, Particle Filters, RBF networks, Reinforcement Learning

employment

Data Scientist NLP and founder, Iceiony Ltd

Sep 2016 - Current

- Designed and developed a prototype for interactive stories with NLP, proving new product feasibility
- Researching neural network techniques to enable better semantic parsing in conversational text *Key Technologies: R, Python, Node.js, Deep Learning (RNN), PyTorch, Dynet*

Developer, Opentable International Ltd - contract

Aug 2017 - Sept 2017

- Migrated legacy solution from outdated .net to a modern version, increasing team productivity by enabling newer development tools
- · Created docker build process to further streamline already impressive deployment and scaling infrastructure
- Developed new features crosscutting .net and node services to create a better experience to customers
 Key Technologies: C#, Node.js, Docker, Mono

Mobile Developer, BBC - contract

Aug 2014 - Sep 2015

- Developing mobile apps for staff and reporters, enabling better access to internal systems
- · Developing software to create authentication access cards, eliminating turnaround time and costs to suppliers
- Setting up build and infrastructure automation, streamlining the software development process Key Technologies: C#, Java 7, Reactive Extensions, Windows Phone, Android, Jenkins, Chef

Software Developer, Wonga.com

Jun 2013 - May 2014

- · Defining the internal service oriented architecture, that improved system maintenance and scalability
- Implementing new back-end service features, enabling new types of loans to be served to customers
- Adding continuous integration tooling, which improved the robustness of deployments Key Technologies: C#, NserviceBus, Nhibernate, Jenkins, Powershell

Software Engineer, Wiggle ltd

Apr 2011 - Jun 2013

- · Developing and refactoring legacy consumer site, that gradually improved the rate of feature development
- · Automated load testing, which highlighted devastating issues experienced at peak website traffic
- Developed and integrated internal systems using micro-services architecture, which solved reliability issues experienced across the company

Key Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, MVC2, T-SQL, NserviceBus, RavenDB, Python, Micro-Services

education

MSc. Computational Neuroscience and Cognitive Robotics, University Of Birmingham,

2016

Focused on computational methods, modeling and neural networks

Graduated with distinction

MSc. Computer Security, University Of Birmingham,

2010

Graduated with distinction

Oracle Academic Initiative, University Of Bucharest, Romania,

2009

BSc. Computer Science, University Of Bucharest, Romania,

2009

Received scholarship for academic performance

Equivalent of distinction

Diploma for Excellence in Computer Science, National Center For Excellence, Romania,

2006

Awarded for academic performance in advanced algorithmics

references

Available on request